Calvin Fuller is about to break curfew...by 1500 years.
A Kid in King Arthur's Court is a adventure, fantasy,
comedy film directed by Michael Gottlieb.
A Southern California kid named Calvin Fuller is magically transported to the medieval
kingdom of Camelot through a crack in the ground caused by an earthquake.
Once there, he learns he was summoned by the wizard
Merlin, who needs Calvin to save Camelot.
Using dazzling modern inventions, can Calvin help King Arthur
retain his crown and thwart the evil Lord Belasco?
Calvin Fuller, played by Thomas Ian Nicholas.
King Arthur, played by Joss Ackland.
Lord Belasco, played by Art Malik.
Master Kane, played by Daniel Craig.
Princess Sarah, played by Kate Winslet.
Princess Katey, played by Paloma Baeza.
A Kid in King Arthur's Court is a 1995 adventure comedy fantasy film directed by
Michael Gottlieb (in his final directorial film before his death in 2014).
It is loosely based on the Mark Twain 1889 novel A Connecticut Yankee in King Arthur's
Court, previously filmed by Disney as Unidentified Flying Oddball in 1978.
The film stars Thomas Ian Nicholas, Joss Ackland and Art Malik, and is notable for
being one of the first film roles of Daniel Craig and Kate Winslet.
In the film, a teenaged baseball player from the suburbs of Los Angeles is swallowed by the ground during an
earthquake, but somehow time travels to the court of an elderly King Arthur in the 6th century.
He is thought to be a messianic figure from Merlin's prophecies.
The time-traveler develops a crush on young Princess Katey, but the girl is kidnapped in an
effort to blackmail her older sister into marrying one of the courtiers.
The film explores themes of time travel,
earthquake, camelot, king arthur, medieval.
The tone is lighthearted.